netop.com 2016-03-09

# Cookies Policy

  * Company

###  **What are cookies?**

Cookies are the small text files saved on your computer or mobile device when you browse the web. These files contain information about your visit and are used to improve your user experience on individual sites.  The information collected allows websites to remember you—not you the person, rather they remember how you enter, use and exit the site—and tailor your future visits accordingly. With that information, websites run faster and more efficiently.

 **Cookies are not:**

  * Viruses
  * Capable of being programmed
  * Capable of spreading malware
  * Capable of identifying you personally

###  **Does Netop use cookies?**

When you visit Netop, we automatically collect information via cookies. Below is a list and description of the first-party and third-party cookies we use.

#### First party cookies enabled on Netop websites

**Cookie Type** | **Cookie Name(s)** | **Description** | **For More Information**  
---|---|---|---  
SSO  | NETOPSSOSID  | This cookie enables us to automatically log our users in to our applications, so users do not need to log in each time they visit the site. It keeps user preferences stored so users can easily download products, trials and other resources. Ultimately this cookie helps us deliver a more customized website experience for individual users.  | [ Wikipedia: Single sign-on](http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Single_sign-on)  
PHP Session  | fe_typo_user  | This cookie allows the site to keep persistent information across pages, based on the users' preferences and site activity, for example language preferences.  | [ Wikipedia: Session ID](http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Session_ID)  
NginX  | NetopUS_cookie, lgeEUclients_cookie  | These cookies allow our servers to optimize load balancing and deliver resources dynamically from our Content Delivery Network (CDN). This essentially gives users a better experience with a faster website.  | [ Wikipedia: Content Delivery Network](http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Content_delivery_network)  
Live Guide  | All cookies starting with "LiveGuide_" | These cookies are used to collect information regarding how a user navigates to and through a site. The data is regarding referral page, landing page and time spent on site. This information is used in Live Guide, our chat platform, to better help the customers that are requesting a live chat interaction. | [ Live Guide Cookies](http://kb.netop.com/article.php?id=222)  
WebConnect | SESSIONID | This cookie allows the WebConnect sites hosted by Netop to keep persistent information across pages, based on the current logged on user. This cookie is only applicable when logging on directly to the Connection Manager. | [ Wikipedia: Session ID](http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Session_ID)  
  
#### Third party cookies enabled on Netop websites

**Cookie Type** | **Cookie Name(s)** | **Description** | **For More Information**  
---|---|---|---  
Google Analytics  | __utma, __utmb, __utmc,__utmz  | These cookies are used to collect information about how visitors use our site. We use the information to compile reports and to help us improve the site. The cookies collect information in an anonymous form, including the number of visitors to the site, where visitors have come to the site from and the pages they visited.  | [ Google Privacy Policy](http://www.google.com/analytics/learn/privacy.html)  
Salesforce  | __ktv, __kti, __kts, __ktt, BIGipServerlct-pool, webact, s_vi  | These cookies are used to collect information for sales and marketing purposes in order to make customer communications relevant and help us understand the performance of our marketing campaigns. Any data collected is used only for internal purposes and with expressed consent of the user.  | [ Salesforce Privacy Policy](http://www.salesforce.com/company/privacy/full_privacy.jsp)  
vBulletin  | bb_sessionhash, bb_lastvisit, bb_lastactivity  | These cookies are used to collect user statistics so that we can see which topics are the most relevant for users and similar analysis. The data is anonymous and helps us make the forum more effective and useful for its users.  | [ vBulletin Privacy Policy](https://www.vbulletin.com/privacy.php)  
AddThis  | uid, uvc, uit, psc, user_segment, __atuvc  | These cookies are used to collect certain anonymous information for use on the “AddThis Platform”. This enables us to use this information via the AddThis Platform for analytics purposes to understand how users are sharing our content across the web and make improvements accordingly.  | [ AddThis Privacy Policy](http://www.addthis.com/privacy/privacy-policy#.T8S_uNUnxhY)  
Double Click  |   | These cookies are used to collect anonymous information for use on Google Adwords. The data is anonymous and helps us deliver relevant advertising to website visitors. |  [Google Privacy Policy](http://www.google.com/policies/privacy/ads/)  
Pardot  | pardot, visitor_id, ipv  |  These cookies are used to collect information for sales and marketing purposes in order to target relevant content to visitors in order to improve their experience on the Netop site. Any data collected is used only for internal purposes with expressed consent of the user.  | [ Pardot Privacy Policy](http://www.pardot.com/company/legal/privacy-policy)  
  
### **Can I opt out of them?**

Yes.  Your browser should allow you to refuse incoming cookies as well as delete those already on your computer or mobile device.  Be sure to consult your browser’s help menu for specific instructions.  For additional information about cookies, visit [www.allaboutcookies.org](http://www.allaboutcookies.org/). 

Note: Parts of Netop may not work correctly with cookies disabled.  In order to download products, cookies must be enabled.
